Henry F. Bedfore Collection of Textile Related Photographs 6692 P
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Henry F. Bedfore Collection of Textile Related Photographs
1912
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Henry F. Bedford
6692 P
1 folders
1 file folder
Gelatin silver print, photographs.
Photographs from the March 14, 1912, Lawrence, Massachusetts, textile strike.
10062691
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
R. Miles, October 09, 2017
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, November 28, 2017
Scope and Contents
Photographs showing the end of the March 14, 1912, Lawrence, Massachusetts, textile strike, Big Bill Haywood speaking, strikers' children returning to Lawrence, and Decoration Day (Memorial Day).
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 6692 G: Henry F. Bedfore Collection of Textile Related Graphics
Bread and Roses Strike -- 1912; Children; Labor-related; Socialism -- United States; Strikes and lockouts; Strikes and lockouts -- Textile industry -- Massachusetts -- Lawrence; Textile industry; Textile workers; Textile Workers' Strike, Lawrence, Mass., 1912; Women textile workers; Greenfield (Mass.); Lawrence (Mass.); Lawrence (Mass.) -- History -- 20th century; Ettor, Joseph J.; Giovannitti, Arturo M., 1884-1959; Haywood, William (Big Bill); O'Reilly, James T., 1851-1925; Sawyer, Roland D. (Roland Douglas), 1874-1969; Industrial Workers of the World; Socialist Party of Massachusetts
10062691
- Various photos after strike: parades, meeting on common, Decoration Day, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Mass meeting, Lawrence Common, calling off strike, 1912; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    March 14, 1912. Snapshot gelatin silver print. Image depicts a meeting on Lawrence Common, Lawrence, Mass., where the textile strike was called off. View shows men, women and children standing on Common, listening to IWW leader speaking from grandstand. Written on reverse: Mass Meeting Common March 14, 1912 Calling off strike." 12.75 x 9.75 cm.
    Format: black and white photograph.
  - Item 2: Leading the parade when children came home, 1912; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Snapshot gelatin silver print, [1912]. Image depicts two little girls, holding flower baskets, leading a group of Ayer Mill Spinning Room workers in the parade celebrating the return of children of strikers who had been removed from Lawrence, Mass., during the textile strike of 1912. Written on reverse: "Leading the parade when kiddies came home." 12.75 x 9.75 cm.
  - Item 3: At railroad station waiting for children to come home, 1912; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Snapshot gelatin silver print, [1912]. Image depicts crowd at B&M (Boston & Maine) railroad station, waiting for the return of children of strikers who had been removed from Lawrence, Mass., during the textile strike of 1912. Written on reverse: "At B & M. station waiting for kiddies to come home." 13 x 9.75 cm.
  - Item 4: I.W.W. parade Decoration Day, 1912; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Snapshot gelatin silver print. Image depicts parade through Lawrence, Mass., on Decoration Day (now known as Memorial Day) in 1912, two months after textile strike was over. Written on reverse: "I.W.W. parade Decoration Day 1912." 13 x 9.75 cm.
  - Item 5: Parade for children coming home, 1912; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Snapshot gelatin silver print. Image depicts parade through Lawrence, Mass., when children of strikers who had been removed from Lawrence during the textile strike returned home. Visible are crowds of onlookers; several horse-drawn wagons containing children; band. Written on reverse: "When "kiddies" came home." 13 x 9.75 cm.
  - Item 6: Leaving mass meeting on Lawrence Common, 1912; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    March 14, 1912. Snapshot gelatin silver print. Image depicts people leaving the mass meeting on Lawrence Common, Lawrence, Mass., on March 14, 1912, after the textile strike was declared off. Written on reverse: "Leaving Mass Meeting Common March 14, 1912 Strike declared off." 12.75 x 9.75 cm.
  - Item 7: Grave of Ramy, Decoration Day 1912, black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Snapshot gelatin silver prin. Image depicts large crowd at grave of boy apparently killed [?] or who died during textile strike, with several people laying wreaths. Decoration Day now known as Memorial Day. Written on reverse: "Grave of Ramy (?) boy Decoration Day 1912." 12.75 x 9.75 cm.
  - Item 8: Grave of Annie LoPizzo, Decoration Day 1912, black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Snapshot gelatin silver print. Image depicts a crowd of people laying a wreath on the grave of Anna LoPizzo (name variously spelled as: LoPezza, Lopezza, Lopezzo) on Decoration Day (now known as Memorial Day). LoPizzo was shot and killed on January 29, 1912 while protesting during the textile strike in Lawrence, Mass. Written on reverse: "Grave of Annie La Piza? Decoration Day 1912." 12.75 x 9.75 cm.
  - Item 9: Big Bill Haywood on Lawrence Common, 1912; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    March 14, 1912. Snapshot gelatin silver print. Image depicts William "Big Bill" Haywood of the I.W.W. speaking on Lawrence Common, Lawrence, Mass., March 14, 1912, when the textile strike was called off. Written on reverse: " 'Big Bill' in action March 14, 1912." 13 x 9.75 cm.